allrovi.com 2013-07-26

# Privacy Policy - Rovi Privacy Policy - AllRovi

Review Rovi's legal and privacy notices for details on how we collect, use and protect your personal information on the website.

Your use of and access to any website or software application ('Rovi Property') either (i) made available to you directly or indirectly from this website; or (ii) with a direct link to this privacy policy is subject to this privacy policy. This privacy policy explains the data that we collect and how we use it.

We respect your privacy. If you have any privacy concerns or questions about this privacy policy, you can contact us by email at: [legal@rovicorp.com](mailto:legal@rovicorp.com).

**Contents**  
About us  
Your information  
Tracking and Cookies  
Email  
Which organizations collect the information  
Advertising  
Security  
Children  
Changing your preferences  
Other disclosures  
Overseas transfers  
Your consent  
Your rights  

 ** _ABOUT US AND THIS POLICY_**

All references to "we", "us" or "our" refer to (1) Rovi Corporation and/or one or more of its corporate affiliates (for all users located outside the European Union ('Europe')); and (2) for all users located in Europe, Rovi Europe Limited.

Rovi Corporation is incorporated in the State of Delaware and its principal office is 2830 De La Cruz Boulevard, Santa Clara, California 95050. Rovi Europe Limited is incorporated in England with registered number 0296781 and has its registered office at Malvern House, 14-18 Bell Street, Maidenhead, Berkshire SL6 1BR. 

This policy gives you the details of who we are and the details of our privacy policies, including: what data we collect about you when you use Rovi Property; what organization is collecting the information; how the information will be used or disclosed; what choices are available to you regarding collection and use of the data; what security measures are in place to protect your personal information; and how you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

This policy may be amended from time to time without notice and it is your responsibility to read it carefully and review any changes that may have been made. Since changes will be posted on this page, we encourage you to check this page regularly. 

For all users in locations other than in Europe, this policy, the processing of your online account data and any other data we collect shall be governed by the laws of the State of California and shall be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts in Santa Clara, California. For all users located in Europe, this policy, the processing of your online account data and any other data we collect is controlled by Rovi Europe Limited which is established in England, and subject to any mandatory laws in the country in which the user resides, shall be governed by the laws of and shall be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the Courts of England.

Back to top

 ** _YOUR INFORMATION: WHAT WE COLLECT, HOW WE COLLECT IT, AND HOW IT IS USED_**

In common with most other websites and on-line services, we collect certain data about your visit to the Rovi Properties. Any data we gather through your use of Rovi Property falls into three categories: (1) personal information that you supply to us, such as information you provide when you register (including your e-mail address), create an account, create a user name, complete a survey, enter a contest, or purchase products or services; (2) information that is collected as you use Rovi Property that becomes identified with your personal information; and (3) information that does not directly identify you and is collected as you use Rovi Property, including your IP address, and information gathered with the use of a "cookie" (cookies are discussed further below), and information related to searches or recommendations on Rovi Property. Such information collected includes, without limitation, which pages and content are browsed, interactions with advertising and content, and other data related to preferences and usage. We use this information to better provide products and services, including, without limitation, to better target advertising and content, and to generate statistics and reports.

You may use certain Rovi Property without registering or creating an account. We may nonetheless build a history of your interactions with the Rovi Property even though we don’t know who you are.In respect of certain Rovi Properties which are products, Rovi may also employ update management software to collect installation and registry information from your computer, including product, version, build, language and original equipment manufacturer. Where you use multiple Rovi Properties, Rovi may combine or link information collected from various Rovi Properties and use it for the purposes outlined in this privacy policy.

**Personal information**  
As is common across websites, to use certain features of Rovi Property we ask you to register, create an account, provide your full name and email address and create a password. Once you have created an account, you will have the option to fill out a form (all or portions of which may be included in your profile).  When you create your profile, we collect personal information about you, such as name, address, location, e-mail address, favourite actors, music, etc. which will be stored in order to provide services to you and to conduct activities including, without limitation, using it to process your registration, maintain a profile about you, process your request to receive newsletters and email announcements, or to voluntarily participate in surveys or contests and/or to communicate with you about services and products we think may be of interest to you. 

Rovi may allow you to set up profiles that may be viewed by other users of the Rovi Properties. To enrich your profile you may chose to include some personal information in your public profile so that other users can identify you. You should only include information in your public profile that you do not mind making publicly available without restriction. 

To process your purchase orders we require your name, billing address, phone number, email address, shipping address, credit card information and credit card security codes. We use this information to process your order and, if any questions arise, to contact you about your order. We may also use it to contact you about other products and services we feel may be of interest to you. In general Rovi will try to email you first but may phone or send an electronic message to you if you have provided these details and you consent to our so doing. 

In respect of 'Roxio' branded Rovi Property, registering your product indicates that you have informed us of your interest in receiving offers and information from us and from third parties and we will contact you after registration unless you specify that you do not wish to receive such contact by notifying us at [legal@rovicorp.com](mailto:legal@rovicorp.com). For those who elect to receive such materials from third parties, Rovi may release personal information to those third parties. Information released may include your name, email address and other information supplied in the Rovi registration process.

Personal information is also used to provide personalised services to you, such as show tracking and recommendations.

Back to top

 ** _TRACKING INFORMATION - COOKIES, FLASH COOKIES , CLEAR GIFS, AND IP ADDRESSES_**

We store and track user information by using "cookies" and clear GIFs, which are also sometimes called web bugs or web beacons. Cookies alone do not tell us your e-mail address or other personal information. However, information provided through cookies may be associated with personal information if you provide this information to us by, for example, registering to use certain Rovi Properties. A cookie is data sent to your browser from a web server. It is stored on your computer and contains a unique identifier that allows our sites to recognize your computer. If you have an account with Rovi, a cookie on your computer lets us remember your user name and password so you don't have to re-enter that information each time you visit the site. Another cookie is a Flash cookie that is embedded in the Adobe Flash Player, which is a web tool that allows rapid development of dynamic content. Adobe Flash cookies may be used in certain situations where we use Flash to provide some content such as video clips or animation and to remember settings, preferences and usage. They are similar to 'browser' cookies (as described above) but are managed through a different interface than the one provided by your web browser.

The use of cookies is standard on the Internet and you will find they are currently used by many major websites. You can set your web browser preferences to alert you when a cookie is sent to your hard drive, or to refuse cookies altogether. We do not require you to use cookies, but please keep in mind that certain features and services will not function properly if you set your browser to refuse cookies.

"Clear GIFs" are very small image files that we sometimes place on web pages and within web-based email newsletters or other communication we send. Clear GIFs let us accurately count the number of users who have visited specific pages and the number of times those pages are accessed. Clear GIFs also let us know how many people opened an email. 

We may use cookies, clear GIFs and related tracking technology to collect information such as your browser type, the type of operating system you use, the domain name of your Internet service provider, IP address, pages visited on the site, services used and how you have used them. 

We may provide data about our users, traffic patterns, products, services and site information to third-parties (such as vendors, advertisers and our business partners), but we will use reasonable efforts to provide it in a form that does not directly identify you.

Find out how to disable/enable browser cookies by clicking on the "Manage Cookies" section of the Interactive Advertising Bureau website on the following link <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>. You may access and manage Flash management tools such as flash cookies from Adobe's web site directly at <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager06.html>.

Back to top

 ** _EMAIL_**

Email addresses are used for identification, inviting new friends to Rovi Properties, searching for and finding friends, general communication, order processing and to send notifications to you. To facilitate searching for and finding friends on the Rovi Properties, Rovi allows users to search for other members using text searches, first and last name, email address, and by using other attributes. Users can invite friends to join certain Rovi Properties by sending invitation emails via our automated invitation system. Where permitted by applicable law, Rovi stores these email addresses so that the respondents may be added to the friend list of the member sending the invitations and to establish relationships between users. 

Back to top

 ** _WHICH ORGANIZATIONS ARE COLLECTING THE INFORMATION?_**

When you provide information to Rovi, that information is collected and maintained either by Rovi or by an authorized agent or contractor of Rovi such as web hosting companies, customer care service providers, and transaction processing service providers, unless specifically stated otherwise at the point of collection.

Back to top

 ** _ADVERTISING_**

We may use your personal information and non-personal information to serve ads to you via Rovi Property as well as to provide you with promotions, products and services. We may also use third-party advertising companies and other business partners to serve ads on Rovi Property and provide you with promotions, products and services. These third-party advertising companies and our business partners may be located throughout the world. 

These third-party advertising companies and business partners may receive information relating to the advertisements that they serve you including, without limitation, date and time of ad shown, the banner ad that was shown and your IP address and your interactions with such advertisements. These third-party advertising companies and business partners may use cookies, clear GIFs and anonymous information about your visits to Rovi Property and other websites to measure and improve the effectiveness of their ads, promotions, products and services. This information may also be used for online preference and other targeted marketing purposes. The information received by these third-party advertising companies and business partners is subject to the privacy policies of these third-party advertising companies and business partners. We may be given access to this information by these third-party advertising companies and business partners which we may use for purposes including, without limitation, to better target advertising and content to you and to generate statistics and reports that help us develop our products and services.

With your consent (as indicated when you set up your account) we may make certain information about you (including personal information, where you consent) available to third-party advertising companies and other business partners under agreements between us and those third-party advertising companies and business partners. The third-party advertising companies and business partners will use that information to target advertising to you or provide and market promotions, products and services to you. You may withdraw your consent to our providing your personal information to advertising companies and business partners at any time by adjusting your preferences in the preference page of the relevant Rovi Property. If you do so we will not provide your personal information from the relevant Rovi Property to third party advertisers or business partners from the time you opt out. However where permitted by applicable law, we may still provide them with information that does not directly identify you from which they may send you targeted advertisements.

Many of our advertising partners are part of the Network Advertising Initiative. You may opt-out of behavioral advertising for Network Advertising Initiative member companies by following the link below and opting-out of all or some of the advertising networks: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

Opting out of Flash Cookies is described above in the Advertising section.

Back to top

 ** _SECURITY_**

We use commercially reasonable efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal information. However, due to the design of the Internet, ever-changing technology and other factors outside of our control, we cannot guarantee that communications between you and our servers will be free from unauthorized access by third parties. We will have no liability for disclosure of personal information due to errors in transmission or unauthorized or unlawful acts of third parties. 

You are responsible for the security of your Rovi user name, ID and password. Please take care when using and storing them.

Back to top

 ** _COMMITMENT TO CHILDRENS' PRIVACY_**

Protecting the privacy of children is important to us. For that reason, none of our Rovi Properties are directed at anyone under 13 and they are not structured specifically to attract anyone under 13.  We also do not collect or maintain personal information from those users who we actually know are under 13. Should we learn or be notified that we have collected information from users under the age of 13, we will immediately delete such personal information.

Back to top

 ** _CHANGING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION & PREFERENCES_**

**Your Right to Choose**  
When you register to access certain Rovi Properties, you can let us know that you do not wish to receive announcements from us by opting out at the time you give us your personal information. You may also later opt out of providing us personal identifiable information by changing your preferences in the set up areas of the Rovi Properties or changing the necessary settings in your profile. For certain Rovi Properties opting out may only be possible if you delete your account for that Rovi Property. If you opt out or do not provide your personal information then some services and features (such as personal information services, recommendations and tracking of ratings and likes and dislikes) may not be available to you or may be deleted. All newsletters and email announcements from us will contain an unsubscribe link that also allows you to opt out at any time from these messages.

**Review and Correction**  
You may review and update the personal information that you have provided us by visiting the relevant set up page of the Rovi Property and updating your account profile.

Back to top

 ** _OTHER DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION_**

We will not otherwise use or disclose your personal information without your consent except (i) as described in this privacy policy, (ii) as required by court order or other government or law enforcement authorities in order to comply with legal process or law, (iii) in the event of a merger where another company has acquired the relevant Rovi Property, (iv) in order to protect against the misuse or unauthorized use of Rovi Property, (v) in order to protect and defend our rights and property, or (vi) in order to protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public.

If Rovi sells assets (or the assets of a division or subsidiary) to another entity, including, without limitation, in the event of bankruptcy, or if Rovi (or a division or subsidiary) is acquired by, or merged with, another entity, Rovi may provide to such entity user information (both anonymised and/or aggregate and personal information) that is related to that part of the business that was sold to or merged with the other entity.

**Links to Third Party Websites**  
Rovi Properties may display links to websites operated by third parties. If you click on a link, the relevant third party operator or others may collect data about you when you visit the linked website. They are responsible for the collection and further processing of such data and we have no control over it. We advise you to check the terms of use and privacy policies of any linked websites you visit to find out what data they are collecting and the purposes for which they process your personal data.

Back to top

 ** _OVERSEAS TRANSFERS AND PROCESSING OF YOUR INFORMATION_**

Your personal information may be used by us and our affiliates, subsidiaries and our suppliers who may be located in countries outside the country where you are located or the purposes outlined in this policy to manage Rovi’s global business. The data protection laws in these countries may not offer the same level of protection as those in the country where you are located. By providing your personal information to us you understand and expressly consent to us and our suppliers processing your data in any jurisdiction, including without limitation the United States of America, in accordance with this privacy policy.

Back to top

 ** _YOUR CONSENT_**

**BY USING ANY ROVI PROPERTIES, YOU ARE CONSENTING TO THE COLLECTION AND USE OF YOUR INFORMATION DESCRIBED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND YOU ACCEPT AND AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY.**

Back to top

 ** _YOUR RIGHTS_**

Your European Privacy Rights. If you are located in Europe, some of the data that we process may be protected by data protection laws such as, in the United Kingdom, the Data Protection Act 1998 (the "Act"). Under the Act, you have certain rights to request information about, get access to or request the amendment of any such personal data. If you wish to exercise these rights, please contact us at [legal@rovicorp.com](mailto:legal@rovicorp.com). Please see the UK Information Commissioner's Office website at: <http://www.ico.gov.uk/> for further details.

Your California Privacy Rights. If you are a resident of the State of California, we provide you in this Privacy Policy with information on how to exercise your disclosure choice options such as your right to opt-out (or "unsubscribe") of our use and sharing of your Personal Information for marketing purposes. Therefore, pursuant to the California Civil Code, we are not required to maintain or disclose a list of the third parties that received your Personal Information for marketing purposes during the preceding year. 

If you are a California resident and wish to request information about how to exercise your third party disclosure choices, please send a request by email to our Privacy Administrator at [legal@rovicorp.com](mailto:legal@rovicorp.com) or by postal mail to Rovi Corporation 2830 De La Cruz Boulevard, Santa Clara, California 95050, Attn:Your California Privacy Rights, c/o Privacy Administrator, Legal Department. All requests must be labelled "Your California Privacy Rights" in the email subject line or envelope or post card. For all requests, please clearly state that the request is related to "Your California Privacy Rights", include your name, street address, city, state, zip code and e-mail address (your street address is optional if you wish to receive a response to your request via email) and indicate your preference on how our response to your request should be sent (email or postal mail). We are unable to accept requests via the telephone or by facsimile. We are not responsible for notices that are not labelled or sent properly, or do not have complete information.

Back to top

 **Inquiries**  
If you have any concern about privacy at Rovi, please send us a thorough description of your concern to [legal@rovicorp.com](mailto:legal@rovicorp.com) or the address above, and we will try to resolve it.

This privacy policy was last updated on: September 30th 2011.
